http://www.thelegalassistant.com/privacy-policy

Privacy PolicyPrivacy Policy of thelegalassistant.com websites and services. This Application collects some Personal Data from its Users.Data Controller and OwnerThe Legal Assistant LLC, 258 Palisade Avenue, Garfield, NJ, 07026, U.S.A., privacy@thelegalassistant.comTypes of Data collectedAmong the types of Personal Data that this Application collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies, Usage data, email address, first name, last name, phone number, company name, website, address, username, password, country, state, ZIP/Postal code, city, various types of Data and data relating to the point of sale.Other Personal Data collected may be described in other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text contextually with the Data collection. The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using this Application. Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Application or by the owners of third party services used by this Application, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User. Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for this Application to provide its services.Users are responsible for any Personal Data of third parties obtained, published or shared through this Application and confirm that they have the third party’s consent to provide the Data to the Owner.Mode and place of processing the DataMethods of processingThe Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data. The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.PlaceThe Data is processed at the Data Controller’s operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller.Retention timeThe Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data.The use of the collected DataThe Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Analytics, Contacting the User, Content commenting, Content performance and features testing (A/B testing), Displaying content from external platforms, Handling payments, Hosting and backend infrastructure, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Managing contacts and sending messages, Managing support and contact requests, Registration and authentication, Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting, RSS feed management and SPAM protection.The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.Detailed information on the processing of Personal DataPersonal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:AnalyticsThe services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.Google Analytics (Google Inc.)Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.Place of processing: US – Privacy Policy – Opt OutContacting the UserMailing List or Newsletter (This Application)By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning this Application. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to this Application or after making a purchase.Personal Data collected: company name, email address, first name, last name and phone number.Content commentingContent commenting services allow Users to make and publish their comments on the contents of this Application. Depending on the settings chosen by the Owner, Users may also leave anonymous comments. If there is an email address among the Personal Data provided by the User, it may be used to send notifications of comments on the same content. Users are responsible for the content of their own comments. If a content commenting service provided by third parties is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the comment service is installed, even when Users do not use the content commenting service.Comment system managed directly (This Application)This Application has its own internal content comment system.Personal Data collected: Cookies, email address, first name, last name and website.Content performance and features testing (A/B testing)The services contained in this section allow the Owner to track and analyze the User response concerning web traffic or behavior regarding changes to the structure, text or any other component of this Application.Google Website Optimizer (Google Inc.)Google Website Optimizer is an A/B testing service provided by Google Inc. Google may use Personal Data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyDisplaying content from external platformsThis type of services allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Application and interact with them. This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.Google Fonts (Google Inc.)Google Fonts is a typeface visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.Personal Data collected: Usage data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyGoogle Maps widget (Google Inc.)Google Maps is a maps visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyHandling paymentsPayment processing services enable this Application to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, this Application shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction. Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails containing invoices or notifications concerning the payment.ChargeBee (ChargeBee Inc.)ChargeBee is a payment service provided by ChargeBee Inc.Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyHosting and backend infrastructureThis type of services has the purpose of hosting data and files that enable this Application to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of this Application. Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.Amazon Web Services (Amazon)Amazon Web Services is a hosting service provided by Amazon.com Inc.Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.Privacy PolicyInteraction with external social networks and platformsThis type of services allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Application. The interaction and information obtained through this Application are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network. This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook, Inc.)The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook, Inc.Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyLinkedIn button and social widgets (LinkedIn Corporation)The LinkedIn button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the LinkedIn social network provided by LinkedIn Corporation.Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyTwitter Tweet button and social widgets (Twitter, Inc.)The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter, Inc.Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyReddit button and widgets (reddit inc.)The reddit button and widgets are services allowing interaction with the reddit platform provided by reddit inc.Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyManaging contacts and sending messagesThis type of services makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User. These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.MailChimp (The Rocket Science Group, LLC.)MailChimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC.Personal Data collected: email address.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyAmazon Simple Email Service (Amazon)Amazon Simple Email Service is an email address management and message sending service provided by Amazon.com Inc.Personal Data collected: email address.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyMandrill (The Rocket Science Group, LLC.)Mandrill is an email address management and message sending service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC.Personal Data collected: email address and Usage data.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyManaging support and contact requestsThis type of services allows this Application to manage support and contact requests received via email or by other means, such as the contact form. The Personal Data processed depend on the information provided by the User in the messages and the means used for communication (e.g. email address).Freshdesk (Freshdesk Inc.)Freshdesk is a support and contact request management service provided by Freshdesk Inc.Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyRegistration and authenticationBy registering or authenticating, Users allow this Application to identify them and give them access to dedicated services. Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In this case, this Application will be able to access some Data, stored by these third party services, for registration or identification purposes.Direct registration (This Application)The User registers by filling out the registration form and providing the Personal Data directly to this Application.Personal Data collected: address, city, company name, country, data relating to the point of sale, email address, first name, last name, password, phone number, state, username, various types of Data and ZIP/Postal code.Remarketing and Behavioral TargetingThis type of services allows this Application and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of this Application by the User. This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.AdWords Remarketing (Google Inc.)AdWords Remarketing is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the activity of this Application with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.Place of processing: US – Privacy Policy – Opt OutFacebook Remarketing (Facebook, Inc.)Facebook Remarketing is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Facebook, Inc. that connects the activity of this Application with the Facebook advertising network.Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.Place of processing: US – Privacy Policy – Opt OutRemarketing through Google Analytics for Display Advertising (Google Inc.)Google Analytics for Display Advertising is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the tracking activity performed by Google Analytics and its Cookies with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.Place of processing: US – Privacy Policy – Opt OutRSS feed managementThis type of services allows this Application to manage RSS feeds and the distribution of their content. Depending on the characteristics of the service used, these services may be used to insert ads within the content and to gather statistics data from them.Feedburner (Google Inc.)Feedburner is a service to manage RSS feeds provided by Google Inc. It allows the collection of statistics on what content is consumed and to insert ads in it.Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicySPAM protectionThis type of services analyzes the traffic of this Application, potentially containing Users’ Personal Data, with the purpose of filtering it from parts of traffic, messages and content that are recognized as SPAM.Akismet (Automattic Inc.)Akismet is a SPAM protection service provided by Automattic Inc.Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyGoogle reCAPTCHA (Google Inc.)Google reCAPTCHA is a SPAM protection service provided by Google Inc.Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data.Place of processing: US – Privacy PolicyFurther information about Personal DataSelling goods and services onlineThe Personal Data collected are used to provide the User with services or to sell goods, including payment and possible delivery. The Personal Data collected to complete the payment may include the credit card, the bank account used for the transfer, or any other means of payment envisaged. The kind of Data collected by this Application depends on the payment system used.The Service is not directed to children under the age of 13Users declare themselves to be adult according to their applicable legislation. Minors may use this Application only with the assistance of a parent or guardian. Under no circumstance persons under the age of 13 may use this Application.Cookie PolicyThis Application uses Cookies.Additional information about Data collection and processingLegal actionThe User’s Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Application or the related services. The User declares to be aware that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.Additional information about User’s Personal DataIn addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Application may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.System Logs and MaintenanceFor operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System Logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address).Information not contained in this policyMore details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.The rights of UsersUsers have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above.This Application does not support “Do Not Track” requests. To determine whether any of the third party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.Changes to this privacy policyThe Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Application and can request that the Data Controller removes the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users.Information about this privacy policyThe Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy, prepared starting from the modules provided by The Legal Assistant, LLC.Definitions and legal referencesPersonal Data (or Data)Any information regarding a natural person, a legal person, an institution or an association, which is, or can be, identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information, including a personal identification number.Usage DataInformation collected automatically from this Application (or third party services employed in this Application), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use this Application, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server’s answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User’s IT environment.UserThe individual using this Application, which must coincide with or be authorized by the Data Subject, to whom the Personal Data refers.Data SubjectThe legal or natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization authorized by the Data Controller to process the Personal Data in compliance with this privacy policy.Data Controller (or Owner)The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization with the right, also jointly with another Data Controller, to make decisions regarding the purposes, and the methods of processing of Personal Data and the means used, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Application. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of this Application.This ApplicationThe hardware or software tool by which the Personal Data of the User is collected.CookiesSmall piece of data stored in the User’s device.Legal informationNotice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies.This privacy policy relates solely to this Application.Latest update: February 26, 2016
